[
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 10,
        "y_pos1": 12,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 91,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 90,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 87,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Jester Twin",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A dancing jester",
            "job": "To entertain.",
            "heal": "Perfectly hoppy!",
            "keyword1": "JEST",
            "keyword2": "BARD",
            "answer1": "A jester needs a good bard!",
            "answer2": "Our bard is very good.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou like the music?",
            "yesanswer": "Then you should go to Britain for there lives the best!",
            "noanswer": "A shame, we do!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 16,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 22,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a nameless prisoner",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A ragged soul.",
            "job": "I have none.",
            "heal": "Very poor.",
            "keyword1": "CRIM",
            "keyword2": "PRIS",
            "answer1": "Crime is an evil thing!",
            "answer2": "Here I pay for my crimes!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Are you a pirate?",
            "yesanswer": "You may never complete thy quests, for evil makes not an avatar!",
            "noanswer": "I hope that this is true!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 28,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 226,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Zorin",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise mage",
            "job": "I am here to help thee.",
            "heal": "I am old, very old....",
            "keyword1": "HELP",
            "keyword2": "CAST",
            "answer1": "Seek help in the castles!",
            "answer2": "Seek: the Lycaeum, Empath Abbey, Serpent's Castle!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou go hither?",
            "yesanswer": "Find therein all named Antos and ask of the bell, book, and candle!",
            "noanswer": "Alas."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a nameless prisoner",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A ragged soul.",
            "job": "I have none.",
            "heal": "Very poor.",
            "keyword1": "CRIM",
            "keyword2": "PRIS",
            "answer1": "Crime is an evil thing!",
            "answer2": "Here I pay for my crimes!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Are you a pirate?",
            "yesanswer": "You may never complete thy quests, for evil makes not an avatar!",
            "noanswer": "I hope that this is true!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 89,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a nameless prisoner",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A ragged soul.",
            "job": "I have none.",
            "heal": "Very poor.",
            "keyword1": "CRIM",
            "keyword2": "PRIS",
            "answer1": "Crime is an evil thing!",
            "answer2": "Here I pay for my crimes!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Are you a pirate?",
            "yesanswer": "You may never complete thy quests, for evil makes not an avatar!",
            "noanswer": "I hope that this is true!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 88,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a nameless prisoner",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A ragged soul.",
            "job": "I have none.",
            "heal": "Very poor.",
            "keyword1": "CRIM",
            "keyword2": "PRIS",
            "answer1": "Crime is an evil thing!",
            "answer2": "Here I pay for my crimes!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Are you a pirate?",
            "yesanswer": "You may never complete thy quests, for evil makes not an avatar!",
            "noanswer": "I hope that this is true!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 88,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 19,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a nameless prisoner",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A ragged soul.",
            "job": "I have none.",
            "heal": "Very poor.",
            "keyword1": "CRIM",
            "keyword2": "PRIS",
            "answer1": "Crime is an evil thing!",
            "answer2": "Here I pay for my crimes!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Are you a pirate?",
            "yesanswer": "You may never complete thy quests, for evil makes not an avatar!",
            "noanswer": "I hope that this is true!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 179,
        "x_pos1": 14,
        "y_pos1": 23,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 50,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a reaper",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A reaper",
            "job": "I kill adventurers!",
            "heal": "Not so good, no one to eat in here!",
            "keyword1": "KILL",
            "keyword2": "THIN",
            "answer1": "There is a thing which can kill many!",
            "answer2": "Knowledge of it is found at Buccaneer's Den!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Will you seek this thing?",
            "yesanswer": "It brings great power!",
            "noanswer": "Then thou must be stupid."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Le Chef",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A person with a white hat.",
            "job": "I am the chef.",
            "heal": "Well.. All but my finger, which I cut!",
            "keyword1": "FOOD",
            "keyword2": "COOK",
            "answer1": "Food, glorious food, to cook is my life!",
            "answer2": "Cooking is a practiced art.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you eat?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should try my soup!",
            "noanswer": "Then thou must be a spiritualist!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Le Chef",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A person with a white hat.",
            "job": "I am the chef.",
            "heal": "Well.. All but my finger, which I cut!",
            "keyword1": "FOOD",
            "keyword2": "COOK",
            "answer1": "Food, glorious food, to cook is my life!",
            "answer2": "Cooking is a practiced art.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Do you eat?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should try my soup!",
            "noanswer": "Then thou must be a spiritualist!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 29,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 12,
        "y_pos1": 19,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A burly guard",
            "job": "I guard the castle and my liege!",
            "heal": "Great!",
            "keyword1": "GUAR",
            "keyword2": "LIEG",
            "answer1": "A guard must be a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I serve Lord British!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou should be a guard!",
            "noanswer": "Still flee not from battle!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 87,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Jester Twin",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A dancing jester",
            "job": "To entertain.",
            "heal": "Perfectly hoppy!",
            "keyword1": "JEST",
            "keyword2": "BARD",
            "answer1": "A jester needs a good bard!",
            "answer2": "Our bard is very good.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou like the music?",
            "yesanswer": "Then you should go to Britain for there lives the best!",
            "noanswer": "A shame, we do!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 85,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 11,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 17,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Juliet",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A fair maiden.",
            "job": "I can help thee.",
            "heal": "Fine thanks.",
            "keyword1": "HELP",
            "keyword2": "ONE ",
            "answer1": "Seek ye to know how the eight virtues form into the three principles.",
            "answer2": "Seek ye to know what one thing the three principles of virtue combine into!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye this?",
            "yesanswer": "Now the one!",
            "noanswer": "Seek it!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 94,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Joshua",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise mage.",
            "job": "I can help.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "HELP",
            "keyword2": "RIDD",
            "answer1": "The riddle!",
            "answer2": "If the eight philosophies of avatarhood combine into and are made from truth, love & courage...",
            "yesnoquestion": "More?",
            "yesanswer": "What one thing creates and is created by all truths, all love & all courage?",
            "noanswer": "Oh."
        }
    }
]